

# MINH TRAN NGUYEN

DIGITAL & GROWTH MARKETING

PHONE

E-MAIL

1 15

The impact of technology on marketing and communication is immeasurable, witnessed through a decade of experience in digital marketing in Vietnam. A diverse background in corporate and agency roles has honed skills in branding and strategy, utilizing these tools to create successful outcomes.

# Marketing Strategies Digital Media Performance User Acquisition Analytical thinking Problem Solving

## **EDUCATION**

2009 - 2012

SKILLS

Intermediate Professional Education at Ton Duc Thang University

Informatic Technology

#### REFERENCES

Tran Quynh Hoa exCMO KiotViet

Na Dai Kang exCEO XLE Group

For reference contact information, please ask me!

#### LANGUAGE

Vietnamese English

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

GoodFood Co. Ltd - Food Distribution Oct 2023 - April 2024

# Digital Marketing Manager

- Overseeing the overall digital marketing strategy, developing, implementing, tracking, and optimizing digital marketing campaigns to ensure digital growth for B2B.
- Support the online retail team to optimize the e-commerce platform, set up internal and external advertising as well as deploy Martech tool/platform to operate retail activities.

# KiotViet - Software Technology | Oct 2022 - April 2023

Growth Marketing Manager | Digital Performance & Community

- Generate leads through media performance and product awareness to promote product growth.
- Create and oversee a digital marketing strategy that promotes brand love, brand positioning, and brand community.
- Work alongside the brand team to develop an all-encompassing communication plan for the products.

# Remote Worker - Covid Pandemic Jul 2021 - Aug 2022

Head of Game Marketing VN - 8vers Studio | Gamefi & blockchain technology

 This role entails overseeing all marketing activities for our game products, including user growth, community building, and strategic cooperation with game publishing partners.

#### Content Licensed Manager VN - Video Intelligence AG | Adnetwork

- Establish a repository of resources for the network.
- Link content publishers with our advertising network.

# XLE Group | Sport & Entertainment | Jul 2019 - Feb 2021

#### Digital Manager | Head of Digital

- Oversee digital media operations, sports merchandise sales, and development of new digital products for the sports platforms within the group.
- Utilize measurement tools and resources to improve proficiency.
- Offer expertise in metrics and support to another department, including training staff in performance management processes.
- Work collaboratively with media partners like Shopee, Tiktok,
   VTVcab, FPT & NBA to build valuable relationships.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

#### 2022:

The first Gamefi showreel at SeaGames (Esport)

#### 2020:

- Vietnam basketball's first medal campaign at the Seagames.
- The first social application for the Vietnamese student sports festival -VUG Running.
- The Official Platform Online Streaming for NBA & VBA Games.

#### 2019:

Saigon Heat Stories & Historical winner at VBA

#### 2018:

- Diana Thematic Campaign with avg. 25,000 visitors for 2 concerts.
- Đầm Lầy One of the first fictional characters to I on social networks

#### 2017:

Yamaha Motors's most popular product launch of the year.

#### 2014:

Castrol World Cup - The project created the most social buzz on social networks.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

In addition, I also have more than 7 years of experience working at creative and digital agencies. Deploying many creative projects on social networking platforms, integrated media events and digital advertising.

Dentsu One | May 2018 - Jun 2019

# Social Manager | Digital Strategis

- Digital media planning for clients.
- Manage online operations and advise clients on integrated communications

DNA Experience Consulting | Mar 2016 - Apr 2018

#### Social Platform Manager

- Media & Social Planner
- Manage KOLs & influencers marketing
- Create and manage Google AdWords, Facebook Advertising
- Measure and report the performance of digital marketing campaigns
- Identify social trends, Social Communications
- R&D social Platform tools

DSquare | Oct 2013 - Aug 2015

#### Community | Sr Social Media

- Social Media Plan & execute
- Coordinate the implementation of integrated communication campaigns
- Manage and develop influencer campaigns
- Management Media Booking (Adwords, Display Ads, PR)

Notch JSC | Nov 2011 - Aug 2013

### Social Media Specialist

- Management Media Booking (Adwords, Display Ads, PR)
- Content management (Web Forums fanpage)
- Research and development of social media plan.
- Management for client's event.

